Guide to the Publishers Weekly: Reference Files,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Publishers Weekly: Reference Files,
1909-2007.
35.28 linear feet (84 manuscript boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library Bakhmeteff Archive New York, NY. 10027
6570018
This collection contains of Publishers Weekly’s reference files on publishing houses. Most of the records consist of clippings from Publishers Weekly, but the files also include clippings from other sources, as well as advertisements, annual reports, brochures, catalogs, commemoratives, correspondence, histories, legal records, obituaries, programs, prospectuses, and survey responses.
Historical Note
Publishers Weekly (also known as PW since 2005) was founded in 1872 as The Publishers' Weekly. It is the oldest journal dedicated to the book industry. Originally, the publication served as a catalog for publishers to provide information on new titles to booksellers in a cost-effective way. Over time, the publication expanded to include articles, features, and other items. Book reviews, which have become a major part of the publication, were not added until the 1940s.
Publishers Weekly was founded by R.R. Bowker, which owned and published Publishers Weekly until the company was purchased by Reed Publishing in 1985. Reed Publishing then placed Publishers Weekly under the management of Cahners Publishing Company. Reed Publishing subsequently merged with Elsevier to become Reed Elsevier in 1993. Reed Elsevier maintained ownership of the publication until 2011 when ownership passed to PWxyz, LLC which currently manages the publication.
Scope and Content
This collection contains of Publishers Weekly's reference files on publishing houses. Most of the records consist of clippings from Publishers Weekly, but the files also include clippings from other sources, as well as advertisements, annual reports, brochures, catalogs, commemoratives, correspondence, histories, legal records, obituaries, programs, prospectuses, and survey responses.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series, and filed alphabetically by corporate name.
There are some areas of inconsistency in the filing of publishing houses that have gone through name changes, mergers, or buyouts. These records may be found under the company's most recent name, but may also be filed separately under the names of all of the individual publishing houses. The files often contain cross-references for affiliated publishing houses.
Series I: Reference Files, 1909-2007
Subjects
Booksellers and bookselling.; Publishers and publishing.; Publishers and publishing--United States--Periodicals.; Clippings; Histories; Obituaries; Periodicals; Publishers' weekly.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
This collection was donated by Reed Business Information, a division of Reed Elsevier Inc., in October 2007.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Series I: Reference Files, 1909-2007
  - AA - AE, 1909-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - AF - AL, 1912-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AM - AQ, 1909-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AR - AZ, 1917-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - A - AE, 1949-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - ABC Publishing, 1978-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abelard-Schuman Ltd., 1950-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Academic Press, 1950-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ace Books, Inc., 1938-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Harry N. Adams, Inc., 1949-2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Addison-Wesley, 1952-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - AF - AL, 1951-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Allyn and Bacon, 1932-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Amadeus - American Sports, 1932-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - American Bible Society, 1922-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - American Book Company, 1921-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Heritage, 1954-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - American Technical Society - Anvil Books, 1932-2005 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Andrews, Michael and Parker, 1933-2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - AP, 1954-2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts
    - 1921-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - History, 1915-1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Staff, 1916-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AR, 1952-2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Arbor House, 1973-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Arno Press, 1967-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Arco Publishing Company, 1942-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - AS, 1939-2005 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - AT - AZ, 1932-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Atheneum Publishers, 1959-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Atlantic Monthly--Little, Brown, 1939-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Avon Books
    - 1931, 1941-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - Suit 1942 (Confidential), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Case #2 February 1943, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - BA - BE, 1909-1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - BF - BL, 1909-1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - BA - BD, 1936-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Ballantine Books
    - 1952-1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1978-2004 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bantam Book
    - 1945-2006, (5 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 2-6)
    - 1990-2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Barnes and Noble, 1936-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - A.S. Barnes & Company, 1932-1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Basic Books, 1935-2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Beacon Press, 1938-2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Beagle - Benjamin, 1932-2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - The Benjamin Company, 1968-2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Charles A. Bennett Company, Inc., 1938-1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Benson - Beyond Words, 1932-2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Berkley/Jove Publishing Group, 1954-2004 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bertelsmann, 1998-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - BI - BL, 1930-2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bloch Publishing Company, Inc., 1927-1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - BO, 1948-2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company
    (See Also: Howard W. Sams)
    - 1926-1969, (2 Folders) (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - 1970-1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Boni and Gaer, 1946-1949 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    (See Also: Gaer Associates)
  - Boni (Albert and Charles), 1923-1932, 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Boni (Charles) Paper Books, 1929, 1949, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Bradford - Broadman, 1930-2004 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Broadside - Byrum, 1928-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - George Braziller, Inc., 1954-2003 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Broderbund, 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bruce Publishing Company (Old), 1932-1976 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - CA - CE, 1909-1959 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - CF - CL, 1909-1954 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - C - Canfield, 1947-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Cahners Publishing Company, 1986-2005, (5 Folders) (Box 10, Folder 3-7)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1930, 1948-2004 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Capability's - Caxton, 1947-2004 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Carroll & Graf, 1983-2005 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Caxton Printers, Ltd., 1934-1966 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - CBS Publishing Group, 1967-1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Publishers CE, 1949-2005 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Publishers CHA, 1939-2003 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Publishers CHE, 1938-2006 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Chelsea House, 1941-2005 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Children's Press, 1947-1995 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Chilton Book Company, 1956-1997 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Chronicle Books, 1993-2005 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - CI-COM, 1947-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Collier Books (Crowell Collier Macmillan), 1988-1997 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - William Collins Publishers (Formerly Collins & World; World Publishing Company), 1941-1997 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University Press, circa 1930-2003, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Compton (F.E.) & Company, 1926-1998 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - CON-COP, 1945-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
  - Contemporary Books (Formerly Henry Regnery Company), 1947-2002 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - COR-COW, 1938-2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University Press, 1951-1998 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Covici, Friede, 1929-1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, Inc. (Formerly Coward, McCann, Inc.), 1919-1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    (See Also: Putnam Publishing Group)
  - Cowles Communications, 1966-1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - CR-CY, 1945-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
  - CR-CZ, 1909-1955 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Creative Age, 1941-1952 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Crowell Collier & Macmillan, Inc.
    (See Also: Collier Books)
    - 1941-1965, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Staff, 1935-1978 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - T. Y. Crowell Company, 1934-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Crown Publishers, 1942-2005, (4 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 2-5)
  - Cupples and Leon, 1909-1956 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - DA, 1927-2003 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - John Day Company, 1926-1976 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Stephen Daye, Inc. (Vrest Orton), 1930-1949 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - DE, 1932-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
  - Delacorte, Dell, 1957-2004 (3 foldrers) (Box 15, Folder 4-6)
  - DF - DQ, 1909-1953, (2 Folders) (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - DI - DN, 1942-2005 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Dial Press, 1932-2004 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Disney, 1990-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - DO - DQ, 1920-2005 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Dodd, Mead and Company
    - 1932-1988 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - History, 1915-1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Staff, 1945-1988 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Dorling Kindersley (DK) Publishing, 1990-2005 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Doubleday and Company
    - 1909-1954 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 1909-2006, (7 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
    - 1985-2006 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      (Includes material on James Frey and the Da Vinci Code)
    - Affiliates, 1933-1995 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Bindrim Libel Case, 1979-1982 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - History, 1917-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Personnel, 1934-1949 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Staff, 1950-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
  - Dover Publications, 1945-2005 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - DR - DZ, 1910-1997, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - Duell Sloan and Pearce
    - 1939-1975 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - History, 1939-1981 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - E.P. Dutton and Company
    - 1920-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    - Dutton Books (NAL), 1990-2005 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - History, 1923-1989 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Staff, 1946-1993 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - EA - EZ, 1909-1921 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - E - EM, 1945-2002 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - E - EM, 1945-2002 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Educational Development Corporation (EDC), 1974-1976, 1993-2006 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Eerdmans Publishing Company, 1938-1980 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - EN - EZ, 1932-2005 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica
    - 1933-2006, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 6-8)
    - Films; Press, 1944-1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - F - FA, 1949-2005 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - F - FE, 1909-1969 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1946-2006, (5 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 2-6)
  - Fawcett Publications (Gold Medal Books), 1943-1996 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - FE - FJ, 1956-2004 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - FF - FL, 1016-1955 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Fell (Frederick), Inc., 1943-1985 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Field Enterprises, 1944-1991 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    (See Also: S & S; Pocket Books; Quarrie)
  - Donald I. Fine, 1984-1997 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - FL - FO, 1946-2004 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - FM - FQ, 1910-1952 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Follett and Company (Formerly Wilcox and Follett), 1918-1959 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Foreign, 1920-1921 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - FR - FU, 1909-2004 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - France--Publishers--Librarire Hachette, 1931-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Franklin Book Programs (Formerly Franklin Publications)
    - 1952-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
    - Newsletter, 1959-1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Franklin Electronic Publishers, 1993-2005 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Free Press, 1947-2006 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - French and European Publications, 1935-1988 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Wilfred Funk, Inc., 1932-1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Funk and Wagnalls, 1936-1997 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - GA - GZ, 1909-1921, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - GA - GG, 1920-2002 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Gaer Associates, Inc. (Formerly Boni and Gaer), 1949 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Gale, 1972-2002 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Garden City
    - 1932-1960 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Staff, 1942-1960 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Bernard Geis/Associates Biogs: Publishers, 1959-1981 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Gemstar, 2000-2003 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - GH - GP, 1938-2005 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Ginn and Company, 1916, 1926-1998 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - David R. Godine, 1971-1998 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Golden Books Family Entertainment, 1996-2005 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Golden Press, Inc., 1942-1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    (See Also: Pocket Books; S & S)
  - GRA - GRE, 1938-2005 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Greenberg: Publisher, 1925-1958 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Greystone Corporation, 1941-1976 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - GRI - GU, 1940-2005 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Grolier, Inc. (Formerly Grolier Society)
    - 1936-1977 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - 1936-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - Grosset and Dunlap
    - 1915-2001, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
    - Staff, 1936-2000 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Grove Press
    - 1952-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 26, Folder 6-7)
    - Lady Chatterley's Lover, 1959, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Grove/Atlantic, 1989-2005 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1986-1989 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Gulf and Western
    (See S & S-History)
  - HA - HE, 1910-1957 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - HA - HAN, 1934-2004 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Haights Cross, 1998-2004 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Haldeman-Julius, 1923-1978 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Hammond, Inc. (Formerly C.S. Hammond and Company), 1942-1999 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - HAR - HAZ, 1933-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 8-9)
  - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich
    - 1920-2006, (5 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - History, 1942-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
    - Staff, 1919-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
  - Harcourt General, Inc., 1991-2001 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Harlequin Books, 1973-2006 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1910-1958, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - Harper and Row (Formerly Harper and Brothers)
    - 1960-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
    - 1978-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 1-3)
    - History, 1923-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
    - Staff, 1915-1989, (3 Folders) (Box 30, Folder 6-8)
  - HarperCollins
    - 1990-2006, (5 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
    - History, 1987-1992 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Staff, 1990-1996 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Harvard University Press, 1933-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - Hastings House, 1941-1989 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Hawthorn Books, 1954-1989 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    (See Also: American Elsevier)
  - HE - HEM, 1958-1996 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - HEN - HEY, 1945-2002 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Hearst Corporation, 1965-2002 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    (See Also: Morrow, Avon, Arbor)
  - Heath (D.C.) and Company
    - 1910-1995 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Staff, 1927-1977 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - HI, 1935-2003 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Hicks, Muse, 1998-1999 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - HMH - Horizon, 1948-2003 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Holiday House, 1935-2005 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston (Formerly Henry Holt and Company)
    - 1932-2006, (3 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1-3)
    - History, 1910-1985 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Staff, 1920-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 5-6)
  - Holtzbrinck, 1973-2006 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Horn Book - Hyperion Press, 1946-2004 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Houghton Mifflin
    - 1938-2006, (5 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 2-6)
    - History
      - 1914-1994 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - 1914-1994 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Staff, 1934-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 2-3)
  - Hungry Minds, 1991-2002 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Hyperion Books (Disney), 1991-2006 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - I, 1942-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 6-7)
  - IF - IZ, 1909-1960 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Indiana University Press, 1950-2004 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Intext (International Textbook Company), 1942-1979 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Iowa State University Press, 1948-2004 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Richard D. Irwin, 1946-1994 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - JA - JZ, 1910-1920, 1943 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - J, 1920-2003 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Publication Society of America, 1938-1988 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press, 1932-2003 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Jove Books/Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1977-1981 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - KA - KI, 1909-1959 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - K - KI, 1910-2005 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - P.J. Kenedy and Sons, 1932-1969 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Mitchell Kennerley, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Kensington, 1974-2005 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - KL - KU, 1938-2002 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Knickerbocker Publishing Company, 1945-1948 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Alfred A. Knopf
    - 1927-2007, (4 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 5-8)
    - 1992-2007 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - History, 1915-1990 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Marchetti--CIA Case, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Staff, 1947-1995, (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
  - Knowledge Industry Publications, 1969-1990 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Kodansha America, 1989-2003 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - LA - LE, 1948-2003 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - LA - LZ
    - 1909-1973 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - 1909-1973 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Landoll's, 1997-1999 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Lazare, Edward (American Book Prices Current), 1945-1960 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    (See Also: Bowker Company: Books; Staff)
  - Leapfrog, 2001-2004 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - 1959-2006 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - LI - LL, 1944-2005 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Library of America, 1979-2004 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - J.B. Lippincott Company
    - 1932-1995 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - History, 1852, 1909-1981 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Staff, 1920-1985 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Little, Brown and Company
    - 1941-1981 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - 1982-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
    - History, 1909-1992 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Staff, 1921-2001 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Litton Educational Publishing, 1968-1981 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Liveright, 1923-1987 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - LO - LY, 1984, 1998-2003 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Long and Smith, Inc., 1930-1935 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Longman, Inc./Longmans, Green and Company, 1948-1987 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Longstreet Press, 1988-1999 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Lothrop, Lee and Shepard, 1933-1989 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Louisiana State University Press, 1941-1999 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - M - MA, 1946-2001, (2 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 5-6)
  - Mac - Mc, 1926-2005 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Robert M. McBride and Company/Medill McBride Company, Inc., 1911-1960 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - MacFadden-Bartell Corporation, 1940-1980 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - McGraw-Hill
    - 1950-1982, (2 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 10-11)
    - 1983-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    - Annual Reports, 1937-2000, (3 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 3-5)
    - History
      - 1909-1966, (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 6-7)
      - 1967-1993 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Staff, 1930-1996 (Box 43, Folder 2-4)
  - David McKay Company, 1918-1996 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - McLoughlin Brothers, Inc., 1928-1954 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Macmillan Company
    - 1938-1977, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 7-8)
    - 1978-2000 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - History, 1913-2002, (3 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 2-4)
    - Staff, 1915-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 5-7)
    - Macmillan Company (Maxwell), 1989 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Declan X. McMullen Company, 1956-1958 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Macrae Smith Company, 1925-1982 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - A.N. Marquis Company, 1930-1992 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Press, 1957-2003 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - MB - ME, 1932-2005 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Meredith Publishing Company, 1947-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 4-5)
  - Meridian Books, Inc., 1956-1986 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - G. & C. Merriam Company
    - 1932-2003 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - History, 1914-1964 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Staff, 1923-1992 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Webster Dictionary Cases
      - 1909-1940 (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - World Publishing Company, 1940-1949, (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 3-4)
  - Charles E. Merrill, 1932-1995 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Julian Messner, Inc., 1920-1976 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - MF - MN, 1934-2005 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - MF - MZ, 1909-1948 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - M.S. Mill Company, 1937-1965 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Millbrook Press, 1999-2004 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Minton, Balch and Company, 1924-1938 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Miramax Books, 1995-2005 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - MO - MT, 1926-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 13-14)
  - Modern Age Books, 1938-1999 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Modern Library--See Random House
  - William Morrow and Company
    - 1926-2006, (4 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 2-5)
    - Staff, 1926-1996 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - C.Y. Mosby Company, 1926-1998 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Thomas B. Mosher, 1923, 1941-1946 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - MU - MZ, 1946-2004 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Music Corporation of America (MCA), Inc., 1979-1996 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - NA - ND, 1941-2005 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - NE, 1938-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 2-3)
  - NA - NL, 1909-1954 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Walter Neale/Neale Publishing Company, 1920-1947 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Thomas Nelson and Sons, 1910-2006, (4 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 6-9)
  - New American Library, 1948-2004, (3 Folders) (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
  - New Directions, 1940-2003 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - New York Graphic Society, 1954-1988 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - New York University Press, 1941-2003 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - News Corporation, 1991-2004 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - NewStar Media, 1988-2001 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - NI - NZ, 1917-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
  - Noble and Noble, 1938-1977 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - North Point Press, 1980-2003 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - W.W. Norton and Company, 1926-2005, (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 5-7)
  - OA - OL, 1911-1953 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - OA - OM, 1940-2005 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Oblivion Press, 1961-1982 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - ON - OT, 1915-2003 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - OU - OX, 1909-2004 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Oxford University Press
    - 1909-2005, (3 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 3-5)
    - History, 1918-1978, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 6-7)
    - Staff, 1937-1990 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - PA - PD, 1971-2004, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 2-3)
  - Page (L.C.) and Company, 1910-1957 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Pantheon Books, Inc., 1942-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 5-6)
  - Paramount Publishing, 1991-1995 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - PEA-PEO, 1945-2004 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Pearson PLC, 1924-2006, (2 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
  - Pellegrini and Cudahy, 1946-1956, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    (See Also: Farrar, Straus and Cudahy)
  - Penguin Books / Penguin USA / Penguin Putnam, Inc, 1937-2006, (4 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 4-7)
  - William Penn Publishing Company (Formerly Penn Publishing Company), 1932-1968 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - PEP-PF (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Pergamon Press U.S., 1958-1991 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Perigord Press, 1979-1982 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Perseus Group, 1997-2005 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Peter Pauper Press, 1938-1991 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - PF - PL (Old), 1910-1949 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - PH - PL, 1962-2005, (2 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 6-7)
  - Philosophical Library, Inc. (Confidential - Office Use Only), 1943-1987 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Pinnacle Books, 1971-1988 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Pitman Publishing Corporation, 1938-1980 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Platt and Munk, 1915-1990 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Playboy Enterprises, 1965-1982, 2001 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Plenum Publishing Corporation, 1959-1999 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - PM - PQ, 1909-1942, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 14)